Rathal saw at once that the Unsullied Flame was a gift from the Great Sol.
He resolved to harness its power with technology and created Amaterasu.
By the light of Amaterasu's sacred flame, the people began to rebuild.
With its power, they established a new state in the Far East.
To be back on your feet again?
Yeah.
I've missed having you around to keep our self-proclaimed knight in check.
The guy's something else.
Yeah.
There are some old reports lying around, and he got the bright idea to shred him using Excalibur.
Nuts, right?
Yeah.
Try saying something besides yeah, you devil.
Okay.
Hey.
When you talk to Maki and Sister Iris, try to brighten up a little.
They both been worried sick about you.
I know you've got a lot on your mind right now, but you aren't alone in this.
Yeah.
Plus, that tiny brain of yours can only brood so much.
You'll break it.
Shut up, jerk.
Fair warning.
Tamaki's there.
Great.
Toss in the crazy cat girl, too.
Welcome back.
I'm so glad you're okay.
Sorry if I worried you, Sister.
So, how's everyone been?
Well, they'll all be excited to see you.
Shinra, congrats on getting out of there.
I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to visit.
I have been thinking about you, though.
No, it's fine.
You had to stand by in case of a call-out.
Hmph.
Hey there.
Welcome back.
Super glad to see the Adolibursta safe and sound.
What's it gonna take to kill this guy?
It's like he's got nine lives.
Well, look at you.
No big surprise that Heaven rejected a devil.
So you're still here?
They haven't gotten sick of having a brainless night around yet.
Oh, good, you're back.
I'm glad.
Yes, sir.
I'd like you to start compiling the incident reports on the Nether as soon as possible.
But your debrief with the captain takes priority.
Hmph.
So you busted out of there.
About time.
Thank you, sir.
Shinra Kusikabe.
Reporting in.
I'm ready for duty.
Okay.
Got me ready.
I'm ready.
Bystand six with one.
We've lost one...
You got me ready.
Take what you got and leave now.
You're worried I got you right in the back.
Get ready for duty.
I'm ready for duty.
Take what you got and leave now
You're wearing out your welcome
No one here wants to see you here, yeah
Think that you won from day one
But the devil will come
You know just why he wants you, don't you?
You're crooked, desire, it doesn't feel so right
Miscuited, defining, in the point of the reason
You're starting a fire, you're gonna watch it burn
Try to save yourself like you always do
Every bridge we build
You think you're just a burning death
Just burn it down
When everything is gone
You wish you only hurt us out
Heard us out
Screaming
Meiji!
So how's the sixth?
Things going well?
Oh, we're doing just fine, sir
We have Captain Huang, after all
Things are pretty quiet around
What's going on?
So, these are the feet that move faster than light
When blessed with grace
Hmm
Usakabe, you're supposed to be on bed rest, no exceptions
Now go and lie down this instant
We might as well let them finish
I'm afraid there's no stopping this now
Burns is a hardhead
Always has been
And always will be
This is the only kind of communication he understands
Seeing the young man's growth has lit a spark in him
The Captain's blood is set to boil now
You hit the truth!
Nothing you can say can justify that!
Fire soldiers work for the greater good
If a lie can save a life, so be it
Better stand back
I think he's getting warmed up now
The heat coming off and feels like it could crush me
He's like a human furnace
He stokes his inner flame and circulates his heat throughout his body
So that every muscle burns with tremendous power
Captain Burns is now a rolling mass of thermal energy in this state
It's easy to see him as flame given human form
I couldn't afford to tell you the truth
Knowledge can be dangerous and often deadly to the weak
If you want answers, prove you're strong enough to hear them
Convince me you're ready
You're the one who showed up saying you wanted to have a chat about this
So why are you making it difficult now?
Tell me what you said you would!
What's wrong?
Scared you won't impress?
Shut up!
You lion!
Faker!
Think he was about to call the captain a naughty word
It took everything he had to hold back
Okay, you got it
I'll show you for a fact
I'm nowhere near as fragile as you think I am, sir
This is all I could save? One small helpless life?
I'm gonna find it. I'm gonna destroy it. The monster's gonna pay for this. I'll kill it.
You've grown so strong, I can hardly believe it. I'm gonna make you talk if it kills me!
Is that all the resolve you have? It's like the sputtering flame of a candle. Don't take me so lightly. Or you'll be in for an ugly surprise!
Are you sure you won't regret finding out?
I hate fire more than anything, but I joined the fire force. All because I needed to do it.
It's like the sputtering flame of a candle.
I wanted the truth!
completely perpetuated flame of a candle
That tiny sputtering flame you had
Has now grown into a raging inferno
It's been a long time
My arm stings where you hit me
That's proof of your strength
And what's more
You have the resolve to see this through
I'll tell you everything
First off, as you've no doubt guessed
Most of what you know about that fire is wrong
The servants of the Evangelist
Have been at work for quite some time now
At least 12 years
Tell me if you sense anything
The Evangelist did say this was the place, correct?
Right around here
And knew a Tola burst will soon be born
Oh hell yeah
The Whiteclad knew about that fire well before the first spark even flew
They knew?
Does that mean they're the ones who...
The cause of that fire was perfectly clear
And it wasn't you
I know that
There was a demon infernal there
We are happy to have you, number three
Shinra!
Don't look, honey, you need to run away
Hurry!
You have to get out of here
Shinra
A demon
Come out, Joe!
Where are you?
The source of the fire that changed your life 12 years ago
Was your little brother
Was your little brother, Sho
It was because of Sho's Adola burst
That your third generation abilities were awakened
You understand the reason we keep our eyes covered, right?
Of course I do
Because if we tried to look at the sun directly, it would burn our eyes
Although the sun shines bright, we mortals may not see it
Those who would approach the celestial must feel it in their hearts
You understand the reason we keep our eyes covered, right?
Of course I do
Because if we tried to look at the sun directly, it would burn our eyes
Although the sun shines bright, we mortals may not see it
Those who would approach the celestial must feel it in their hearts
The horned infernal the demon you saw in your home was my mom
No, that can't be right everything I've done since that day was to find that infernal and kill it
So show caused the fire and the demon infernal that I was to blame was my mom
But if mom turned, where did she go?
What happened to her?
The flames had raged for 15 minutes by the time I arrived at the scene
Anyone alive in there?
Why aren't we trying to put out the flames?
We did, but this fire isn't normal
Water doesn't even slow it down
You fight that fire till the hoses run dry
And after that, start spitting
Those of you with powers are coming with me
We'll charge straight in and pull out any survivors
Three, two, one
I think he's alive
We need a paramedic up here now
Sir
Let go of me
My mom and little brother are still trapped inside the house
And there's a demon in there with them
I have to stop it
So, what do you think?
A fire that won't go out
A demon
Things don't get much worse
I'm going in there
I put the corpse in place to stand in for the mother
Speaking of, tell me
Are you in control?
Hey, how may I?
How goes it?
Talk to me
Did it work or not?
Hey
How may I?
Say something
I'm doing it, so shut your stupid trap, Charon
If you can't help but distract me
Then get lost and die
Why didn't you just answer the first time?
Why should I have?
Would you have helped me if I had?
Of course not
You can't
So shut your ugly, useless face
And stop bothering me
Okay, yeah
My bad
She's scary
If someone wasn't here
By now they'd be
That demon has a baby
Get over here and bring your precious baby with you, Kay
Hold it
The whole place will come down, Sue
Get out of there
That infernal just
Watch your head
A demon infernal
And a dola burst
And a dola link
The old wounds burning out of control
Like when I saw the other world's flame
And lost my eye to it
Mom, Joe, come out!
I'm sorry, but I can't let you go
Surprise, I didn't take him, too
His abilities have been awakened
But his flames are still weak
Think you can...
Yeah
Listen closely
Your mother was killed in that fire
Your brother met the same fate
Why?
Why did you lie to me?
To keep you from getting involved in this mess
If they found out about your powers
If they found out about your powers, they'd have come for you, too
I lied because I wanted the fear of the flames to be strong in you
I wanted you to hate fire so much that you'd never think of using your powers
And no one would ever find out you had them
Well, I do hate fire
Even now
Even knowing that you lied
Whatever caused that fire 12 years ago
Flames are what took my family away from me
And for that, I'll always hate them
That said
It's by using them that you've made it as far as you have
I said what I came to say, so I'll take my leave now
Wait a sec, please
I've got one more question
Have you had an Adola link?
Have you looked at hell for yourself?
Yeah
It cost me an eye, but I've seen the flames of hell
The demon from 12 years ago
Was it an infernal with horns where its eyes should have been?
It was
Then back at the nether
That was her
Where'd my mom go?
Did you see?
I only ever got that one glimpse
If I make another Adola link
Then maybe I can see that infernal again
I could see mom again
But how do I make another link?
That captain
I saw him in Adola
I'm sorry, but
I have to insist you get more rest
You look like him
Who do I look like?
Sounded like you said him
Well, uh
You're Lieutenant Agu, right?
Yes
Well, then I have to ask
Company 4, their captain
Oh, yeah
Captain Suichiro Agu of the 4th is my grandfather
As you've apparently guessed
Uh, why though?
Do you really think I look like him?
No, not really
You just share a couple distinct but very minor features
No need to worry
Why would I worry?
Anyway
Would you be willing to introduce me to Captain Agu?
You're asking to meet my grandfather?
That's my full report
Hmm
So you're banking on the theory that Captain Agu and the Adola Link are connected somehow
That's correct, sir
I recently met a relative of his
Lieutenant Asako Agu of the 6th
I asked her to introduce us
Could work
I was actually just about to get in touch with the chief of the fire defense agency
I'll see if he can reach out to Company 4 on our behalf
But
If we assume the story Captain Burns told you is actually legit
Then the Whiteclad were at the very least involved in the tragedy that took your family from you
I live for the chance to get revenge on that demon
After 12 years
It hurts to think that it might have been my mother
But I was wrong about my brother's death
So I can't rule this out either
Tell me this
If your mother has become an infernal
And it turns out she's still around
Then I'll save her
I'll find a way to turn her back into a human being
I'll see you next time
What a dump
I'm okay
Don't feel bad
I'm a knight
A swordsman
So it makes sense
I'm better at wielding a blade
I'll pretend that this next onion's your head
I can definitely cut this faster than him
Take it easy you two
Hey what?
Oh night king
Latom
I thoroughly enjoy it when gravel learns its place
Hello lieutenant kareem
Oh tamaki
Good to see you're here
Having a good time here
Yeah uh listen
Could you please take me off suspension
We brought this for the party?
Thank you we appreciate it
It's sake should help us make it through this
You know that Shinra's too young to drink right?
Of course we didn't bring it for the kid to drink
It's for adults like us to enjoy
You in a poor should I
I partake only rarely my princess
But here with you tonight
I have such a thirst
Yeah
I might have just a little bit
She's thick but underage
I am not a chunky hookah deal
Never said you were
So uh
It's my pleasure
And honor to be hosting this shindig
We've gathered here to congratulate our friend
I of course am referring to Shinra
Thank you for this food
Latom